<deck name="M5_2 English Vocab Sum">
	<fields>
		<text name='Front' sides='11'></text>
		<text name='Back' sides='01'></text>
	</fields>
	<cards>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>Hit the nail on the head (idiom)</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: Say exactly the right thing or find the real cause of a problem
Thai: พูดตรงประเด็น, พูดถูกเผง</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>Discuss (v.)</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: Talk about something in detail with someone
Thai: สนทนา, ถกเถียง</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>Protest (v.)</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: Show or express strong disagreement, often publicly
Thai: ประท้วง, คัดค้าน</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>Chat (v.)</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: Talk in a friendly and informal way
Thai: คุยเล่น</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>Capricious, Unpredictable (adj.)</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: Changing mood or behavior suddenly; hard to predict
Thai: โลเล, คาดเดายาก</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>Self-assured, Confident (adj.)</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: Feeling sure about your own abilities or qualities
Thai: มั่นใจในตัวเอง</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>Mutter (v.)</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: Speak quietly in a way that is hard to hear, often when annoyed
Thai: บ่นพึมพำ (มักใช้ตอนอารมณ์ไม่ดีหรือรำคาญ)</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>Trustworthy, Reliable (adj.)</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: Can be trusted; dependable
Thai: ไว้ใจได้, พึ่งพาได้</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>Gossip (v.)</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: Talk about other people’s private lives, often unkindly or unnecessarily
Thai: นินทา</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>Have your cake and eat it (idiom)</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: Try to get two opposite benefits at the same time, which is impossible
Thai: จะเอาดีทั้งสองอย่าง (ทั้งที่ทำไม่ได้)</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>Whisper (v.)</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: Speak very softly so that only a few people can hear
Thai: กระซิบ</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>Hit the hay (idiom)</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: Go to bed to sleep
Thai: ไปนอน (ภาษาพูด)</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>Dogmatic, Opinionated (adj.)</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: Strongly sticking to one’s own ideas and not listening to others
Thai: ดื้อรั้น, ยึดติดความคิดเห็นตัวเอง</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>Fishy (adj., idiom)</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: Seeming dishonest, strange, or not right
Thai: มีพิรุธ, น่าสงสัย</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>Stand-offish, Aloof (adj.)</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: Behaving in a distant, unfriendly, or reserved way; not easy to approach
Thai: หยิ่ง, ไว้ตัว, เย็นชา</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>Hit the roof (idiom)</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: Become extremely angry
Thai: โกรธจัด, โกรธจนควันออกหู</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>Sour grapes (idiom)</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: Pretending something you can’t have is not important or not good
Thai: องุ่นเปรี้ยว, ทำเป็นไม่อยากได้เพราะตัวเองไม่มีปัญญาได้</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>Eat my words (idiom)</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: Admit that what you said before was wrong
Thai: ยอมรับว่าสิ่งที่พูดไปนั้นผิด, กลืนน้ำลายตัวเอง</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>Hit it big (idiom)</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: Become very successful or rich suddenly or quickly
Thai: ประสบความสำเร็จอย่างยิ่งใหญ่, รวยเละ</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>Hit the buffers (idiom)</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: Come to a sudden stop and be unable to progress
Thai: หยุดชะงัก, ไปต่อไม่ได้</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>A fish out of water (idiom)</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: Feel uncomfortable because you are in an unfamiliar situation
Thai: คนที่รู้สึกประหม่า/ทำตัวไม่ถูกเพราะอยู่ในที่ไม่คุ้นเคย</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>Make a meal of it (idiom)</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: Make something small seem very serious or important
Thai: ทำเรื่องเล็กให้เป็นเรื่องใหญ่เกินความจำเป็น</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>Hit the road (idiom)</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: Start a journey, leave a place to travel
Thai: ออกเดินทาง</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>Hit the ground running (idiom)</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: Start a new job or activity and work effectively from the beginning
Thai: เริ่มงานได้ทันทีอย่างมีประสิทธิภาพ</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>different</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: (adj.) not the same; unlike in nature, form, or quality
Thai: (adj.) ไม่เหมือนกัน แตกต่างกัน</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>indifferent</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: (adj.) having no particular interest or sympathy; unconcerned
Thai: (adj.) ไม่สนใจ เพิกเฉย เฉยเมย</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>interested</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: (adj.) showing curiosity or concern about something; wanting to know more
Thai: (adj.) สนใจ อยากรู้ในเรื่องใดเรื่องหนึ่ง</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>disinterested</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: (adj.) not influenced by personal advantage; able to judge fairly
Thai: (adj.) ไม่ลำเอียง เป็นกลาง ไม่มีส่วนได้เสีย</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>famous</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: (adj.) known about by many people; widely recognized
Thai: (adj.) มีชื่อเสียง โด่งดัง เป็นที่รู้จักทั่วไป</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>infamous</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: (adj.) well known for being bad or morally wrong
Thai: (adj.) มีชื่อเสียงในทางที่ไม่ดี เลื่องลือในทางลบ</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>flammable</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: (adj.) able to catch fire easily
Thai: (adj.) ติดไฟง่าย ไวไฟ</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>inflammable</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: (adj.) easily set on fire; flammable
Thai: (adj.) ติดไฟง่าย ไวไฟ (เหมือน flammable)</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>savoury</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: (adj.) having a salty or spicy taste, not sweet
Thai: (adj.) มีรสเค็มหรือเผ็ด ไม่หวาน (ของคาว)</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>unsavoury</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: (adj.) unpleasant or morally unacceptable; having a bad taste or smell
Thai: (adj.) ไม่น่าพอใจ น่าสงสัย หรือมีกลิ่น/รสไม่ดี</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>sensible</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: (adj.) having or showing good judgement; reasonable and practical
Thai: (adj.) มีเหตุผล รอบคอบ ใช้วิจารณญาณดี</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>insensible</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: (adj.) unconscious or unable to feel; not aware of something
Thai: (adj.) หมดสติ ไม่รู้สึกตัว หรือไม่ตระหนักถึง</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>valuable</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: (adj.) worth a lot of money; very useful or important
Thai: (adj.) มีค่า มีราคา สำคัญ</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>invaluable</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: (adj.) extremely useful; so valuable that its worth cannot be measured
Thai: (adj.) มีค่ามากประเมินค่าไม่ได้ มีประโยชน์อย่างยิ่ง</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>equally</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: In the same way or to the same degree; treating everyone the same without favoritism.
Thai: ในลักษณะเดียวกัน หรือในระดับเท่า ๆ กัน; ปฏิบัติต่อทุกคนอย่างเท่าเทียม ไม่ลำเอียง</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>equal (adj.)</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: Being the same in quantity, size, degree, or value.
Thai: เท่ากัน มีปริมาณ ขนาด ระดับ หรือมูลค่าเท่ากัน</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>equal (v.)</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: To be the same in value, amount, or effect as something else.
Thai: เท่ากับ หรือมีค่าเท่ากับสิ่งอื่น</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>impact (n.)</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: A strong effect or influence that something has on a person or situation.
Thai: ผลกระทบ หรืออิทธิพลอย่างแรงที่สิ่งหนึ่งมีต่อบุคคลหรือสถานการณ์</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>impact (v.)</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: To have a strong effect or influence on something.
Thai: ส่งผลกระทบหรือมีอิทธิพลต่อ</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>conventional wisdom</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: A commonly held belief or opinion that most people think is true.
Thai: ความเชื่อหรือความคิดที่คนส่วนใหญ่ยอมรับกันทั่วไปว่าเป็นจริง</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>to keep tabs on (sb/sth)</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: To watch someone or something carefully to know what is happening.
Thai: คอยจับตาดู / คอยเฝ้าสังเกตอย่างใกล้ชิด</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>to get away with murder</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: To do something very bad without being punished.
Thai: ทำเรื่องแย่ ๆ แล้วไม่ถูกลงโทษเลย</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>personality (n.)</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: The set of characteristics that make a person different from others.
Thai: บุคลิกภาพ หรือเอกลักษณ์นิสัยที่ทำให้แต่ละคนแตกต่างกัน</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>personal (adj.)</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: Relating to a particular person; private.
Thai: เกี่ยวกับบุคคลใดบุคคลหนึ่ง เป็นเรื่องส่วนตัว</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>personnel (n.)</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: The people who work for an organization.
Thai: บุคลากร หรือพนักงานในองค์กร</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>personalize (v.)</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: To design or change something so that it is suitable for a particular person.
Thai: ทำให้เหมาะสมหรือเฉพาะเจาะจงกับบุคคลใดบุคคลหนึ่ง</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>impersonal (adj.)</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: Not showing personal feelings; not influenced by personal opinions.
Thai: ไม่เป็นส่วนตัว ปราศจากอารมณ์หรือความรู้สึกส่วนตัว</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>result in (phr. v.)</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: To cause something to happen.
Thai: ส่งผลให้ / ทำให้เกิด</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>upbringing (n.)</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: The way that parents care for and teach a child as they grow up.
Thai: การเลี้ยงดูและอบรมสั่งสอนของพ่อแม่ขณะเด็กเติบโต</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>outgoing (adj.)</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: Friendly and eager to meet and talk to other people.
Thai: ร่าเริง เปิดเผย ชอบเข้าสังคม</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>introverted (adj.)</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: Quiet and more interested in one’s own thoughts than in socializing.
Thai: เก็บตัว ไม่ค่อยชอบเข้าสังคม มุ่งอยู่กับตัวเอง</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>extroverted (adj.)</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: Lively and confident; enjoying being with other people.
Thai: ชอบสังคม เปิดเผย ร่าเริงและมั่นใจ</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>confident (adj.)</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: Feeling sure about your abilities or qualities.
Thai: มั่นใจในตนเอง</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>responsible (for) (adj.)</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: Having the duty to take care of something or someone; being to blame for something.
Thai: มีความรับผิดชอบ หรือเป็นผู้รับผิดชอบต่อสิ่งใดสิ่งหนึ่ง</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>sibling (n.)</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: A brother or sister.
Thai: พี่น้องร่วมพ่อแม่เดียวกัน หรือร่วมสายเลือด</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>to look up to (sb)</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: To admire and respect someone.
Thai: เคารพนับถือ ชื่นชมยกย่อง</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>admirer (n.)</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: A person who respects or is attracted to someone.
Thai: ผู้ชื่นชม หรือผู้ที่ชอบ/นับถือใครสักคน</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>admire (v.)</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: To respect and approve of someone or something.
Thai: ชื่นชม ยกย่อง</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>involved (in) (adj.)</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: Taking part in an activity or event.
Thai: ที่มีส่วนร่วม หรือเกี่ยวข้องอยู่ด้วย</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>overlook (v.)</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: To fail to notice or consider something.
Thai: มองข้าม หรือไม่ได้สังเกต</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>accommodating (adj.)</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: Helpful and willing to do things for others.
Thai: ซึ่งให้ความช่วยเหลือ ยืดหยุ่น พร้อมอำนวยความสะดวก</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>receptive (to) (adj.)</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: Willing to listen to and accept new ideas or suggestions.
Thai: เปิดรับ พร้อมรับฟัง และยอมรับแนวคิดใหม่ ๆ</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>participate (in) (v.)</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: To take part in an activity or event.
Thai: เข้าร่วม หรือมีส่วนร่วมในกิจกรรมหรือเหตุการณ์</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>participation (n.)</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: The act of taking part in something.
Thai: การเข้าร่วม หรือการมีส่วนร่วม</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>restriction (n.)</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: A rule or law that limits what people can do.
Thai: ข้อจำกัด หรือกฎที่จำกัดการกระทำ</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>restricted (adj.)</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: Limited or controlled; not allowed to everyone.
Thai: ถูกจำกัด จำกัดขอบเขต หรือไม่เปิดให้ทุกคน</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>manipulative (adj.)</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: Good at controlling or influencing people in a clever but often unfair way.
Thai: ชอบชักใย ควบคุม หรือจูงใจผู้อื่นอย่างเจ้าเล่ห์</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>manipulate (v.)</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: To control or influence someone or something cleverly, often unfairly.
Thai: ชักใยหรือควบคุมผู้อื่นอย่างแนบเนียน มักในทางไม่ยุติธรรม</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>potential (n.)</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: A natural ability or quality that could develop and make someone successful in the future.
Thai: ศักยภาพ หรือความสามารถแฝงที่สามารถพัฒนาได้ในอนาคต</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>cite (v.)</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: To mention something as an example or proof.
Thai: อ้างถึง หรือยกตัวอย่างประกอบ</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>achievement (n.)</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: Something important or difficult that you succeed in doing.
Thai: ความสำเร็จ โดยเฉพาะสิ่งที่ทำได้ยากหรือสำคัญ</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>financial (adj.)</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: Related to money or the management of money.
Thai: เกี่ยวกับการเงิน หรือเรื่องทรัพย์สินเงินทอง</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>disciplined (adj.)</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: Able to control your own behavior and work in an organized way.
Thai: มีวินัย ควบคุมตนเองได้ดี</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>discipline (v.)</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: To train someone to obey rules and control their behavior.
Thai: ฝึกระเบียบวินัย หรือควบคุมพฤติกรรมให้เชื่อฟังกฎเกณฑ์</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>obedience (n.)</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: The act of doing what you are told to do.
Thai: การเชื่อฟัง การปฏิบัติตามคำสั่ง</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>obedient (adj.)</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: Willing to do what you are told to do.
Thai: เชื่อฟัง เชื่อคำสั่ง</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>determine (v.)</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: To decide something officially; or to make something happen in a particular way.
Thai: ตัดสินใจ กำหนด หรือเป็นตัวชี้ขาดให้เกิดผลอย่างใดอย่างหนึ่ง</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>determined (adj.)</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: Having a strong desire to do something and not letting anything stop you.
Thai: มุ่งมั่น ตั้งใจแน่วแน่ ไม่ยอมแพ้</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>negotiation (n.)</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: A formal discussion to reach an agreement.
Thai: การเจรจาต่อรอง เพื่อหาข้อตกลงร่วมกัน</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>negotiate (v.)</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: To discuss something to reach an agreement.
Thai: เจรจาต่อรอง เพื่อให้ได้ข้อตกลง</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>compromise (n.)</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: An agreement where each side gives up part of what they want.
Thai: การประนีประนอม ต่างฝ่ายต่างยอมลดบางอย่างลง</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>compromise (v.)</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: To reach an agreement by each side giving up part of what they want.
Thai: ประนีประนอม หรือยอมปรับลดข้อเรียกร้องเพื่อให้ตกลงกันได้</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>law enforcement (n.)</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: The system or people responsible for making sure laws are obeyed.
Thai: หน่วยงานหรือระบบที่ทำหน้าที่บังคับใช้กฎหมาย เช่น ตำรวจ</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>enforcement (n.)</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: The act of making sure a law or rule is obeyed.
Thai: การบังคับใช้กฎหมายหรือกฎระเบียบ</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>enforceable (adj.)</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: That can be made to happen by law.
Thai: สามารถบังคับใช้ตามกฎหมายได้</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>limelight (n.)</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: Public attention and interest.
Thai: การตกเป็นจุดสนใจของสาธารณชน</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>to gravitate toward (v.)</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: To be attracted to something and move or be drawn towards it.
Thai: ถูกดึงดูด หรือโน้มเอียงไปหาสิ่งใดสิ่งหนึ่ง</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>supporter (n.)</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: A person who approves of and encourages someone or something.
Thai: ผู้สนับสนุน หรือผู้เห็นด้วยและคอยให้กำลังใจ</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>advocate (n.)</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: A person who publicly supports an idea, plan, or way of doing something.
Thai: ผู้สนับสนุนหรือผู้ผลักดันแนวคิด/นโยบายอย่างเปิดเผย</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>advocate (v.)</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: To publicly support a particular idea or way of doing something.
Thai: สนับสนุนหรือผลักดันสิ่งใดอย่างเปิดเผย</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>proponent (n.)</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: A person who supports an idea or plan.
Thai: ผู้เสนอ/ผู้สนับสนุนแนวคิดหรือแผนงาน</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>opponent (n.)</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: A person who disagrees with and fights against an idea or plan.
Thai: ผู้คัดค้าน หรือฝ่ายตรงข้าม</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>override (v.)</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: To be more important than something else; to cancel or replace a decision.
Thai: มีความสำคัญเหนือกว่า หรือยกเลิก/ทับคำตัดสินเดิมด้วยคำตัดสินใหม่</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>sole (adj.)</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: Only; not shared with anyone else.
Thai: เพียงผู้เดียว หรือเพียงอย่างเดียว</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>citation (n.)</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: A reference to a book, article, or study used as evidence.
Thai: การอ้างอิงแหล่งข้อมูล เช่น หนังสือ บทความ หรือการศึกษา</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>success (n.)</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: The achievement of something you wanted or tried to do.
Thai: ความสำเร็จ</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>succeed (v.)</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: To achieve what you were trying to do.
Thai: ประสบความสำเร็จ</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>successor (n.)</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: A person who takes someone else’s place or job.
Thai: ผู้สืบตำแหน่ง หรือผู้รับช่วงต่อ</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>successful (adj.)</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: Achieving good results or achieving what you wanted.
Thai: ซึ่งประสบความสำเร็จ</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>successfully (adv.)</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: In a way that achieves the desired result.
Thai: อย่างประสบความสำเร็จ</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>consensus</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: An opinion that all or most members of a group agree with.
Thai: ความเห็นพ้องต้องกันของคนส่วนใหญ่หรือทั้งหมดในกลุ่ม</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>well-being</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: A general feeling of health, happiness, and being comfortable.
Thai: ภาวะความเป็นอยู่ที่ดี ทั้งด้านสุขภาพ ความสุข และความสบายใจ</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>pioneering</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: Involving new ideas or methods that no one has used before.
Thai: ที่บุกเบิกริเริ่ม ใช้แนวคิดหรือวิธีการใหม่ที่ไม่เคยมีมาก่อน</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>transform</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: To change the form, appearance, or character of something completely.
Thai: เปลี่ยนรูปแบบหรือสภาพของบางสิ่งไปอย่างสิ้นเชิง</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>sustain</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: To provide what is needed for something to exist, continue, or stay at the same level.
Thai: คงไว้/ประคับประคองให้ดำรงอยู่ หรือให้สิ่งที่จำเป็นเพื่อให้ดำเนินต่อไปได้</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>environmentally sustainable</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: Using methods that do not harm the environment and can be continued for a long time.
Thai: ที่เป็นมิตรต่อสิ่งแวดล้อมและสามารถทำต่อเนื่องได้ในระยะยาวโดยไม่ทำลายสิ่งแวดล้อม</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>fertilizer</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: A natural or chemical substance added to soil to make plants grow better.
Thai: ปุ๋ยหรือสารที่ใส่ในดินเพื่อช่วยให้พืชเจริญเติบโตดีขึ้น</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>herbicide</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: A chemical used to kill unwanted plants, especially weeds.
Thai: สารเคมีกำจัดวัชพืชหรือพืชไม่พึงประสงค์</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>intervene</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: To become involved in a situation in order to change it or help solve a problem.
Thai: เข้าไปแทรกแซงหรือยุ่งเกี่ยวเพื่อเปลี่ยนแปลงหรือช่วยแก้ปัญหา</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>intervention</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: An action taken to improve or change a situation.
Thai: การแทรกแซงหรือการเข้าไปดำเนินการเพื่อปรับปรุงหรือเปลี่ยนแปลงสถานการณ์</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>harvest (n.)</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: The time of year when crops are collected and the act of cutting and gathering them.
Thai: ช่วงเวลาเก็บเกี่ยวผลผลิตทางการเกษตร และการเก็บเกี่ยวพืชผล</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>recognize</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: To admit or become aware that something exists or is true.
Thai: ยอมรับหรือตระหนักว่าบางสิ่งมีอยู่หรือเป็นความจริง</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>product</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: Something that is grown or made, usually for sale.
Thai: ผลิตภัณฑ์หรือสิ่งของที่ผลิตหรือเพาะปลูกขึ้นมาเพื่อนำไปขาย</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>sacrifice (v.)</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: To give up something you value in order to get or do something more important.
Thai: เสียสละหรือยอมสละสิ่งที่มีค่าเพื่อสิ่งที่สำคัญกว่าหรือเพื่อผู้อื่น</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>convert</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: To change something from one form, use, or system into another.
Thai: เปลี่ยนแปลงหรือดัดแปลงบางสิ่งให้เป็นรูปแบบหรือการใช้แบบใหม่</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>commission (v.)</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: To officially ask someone to write, make, or create something.
Thai: มอบหมายหรือสั่งทำอย่างเป็นทางการให้ใครสักคนสร้างหรือผลิตบางสิ่ง</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>sustainable (adj.)</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: Able to be continued for a long time without causing damage, especially to the environment.
Thai: ที่ยั่งยืน สามารถทำต่อเนื่องได้โดยไม่ก่อให้เกิดความเสียหาย โดยเฉพาะต่อสิ่งแวดล้อม</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>profit (n.)</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: The money that you earn in business after paying all costs.
Thai: กำไร หรือเงินส่วนที่เหลือหลังหักต้นทุนและค่าใช้จ่ายทั้งหมดแล้ว</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>profit (v.)</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: To get advantage or benefit from something.
Thai: ได้ประโยชน์หรือได้กำไรจากบางสิ่ง</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>donate</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: To give money or goods to help a person or an organization, often a charity.
Thai: บริจาคเงินหรือสิ่งของเพื่อช่วยเหลือบุคคลหรือองค์กรโดยไม่หวังผลตอบแทน</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>donor</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: A person who gives money, goods, or help to an organization or person.
Thai: ผู้บริจาคหรือผู้ให้การสนับสนุน</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>mission</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: An important official job that a person or group is given to do.
Thai: ภารกิจสำคัญที่ได้รับมอบหมายอย่างเป็นทางการให้ทำ</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>desert (n.)</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: A large, hot, dry area of land with very few plants.
Thai: ทะเลทราย พื้นที่แห้งแล้งร้อนจัดและมีพืชขึ้นน้อยมาก</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>border (n.)</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: A line between two countries or areas.
Thai: พรมแดนหรือเขตแดนระหว่างสองประเทศหรือสองพื้นที่</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>develop (v.)</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: To grow or change into a more advanced, larger, or stronger form.
Thai: พัฒนา หรือทำให้เติบโต/ก้าวหน้า/ดีขึ้น</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>maintain</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: To keep something at the same level or in good condition.
Thai: คงไว้หรือดูแลรักษาให้อยู่ในสภาพเดิมหรือสภาพดี</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>venture (n.)</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: A business project or activity that involves taking risks.
Thai: โครงการหรือกิจการที่มีความเสี่ยง</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>venture (v.)</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: To do something or go somewhere that involves risk or danger.
Thai: เสี่ยงทำหรือเสี่ยงไปยังที่ใดที่หนึ่งแม้อาจมีอันตรายหรือความล้มเหลว</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>demand (n.)</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: The need or desire of customers for goods or services.
Thai: อุปสงค์หรือความต้องการซื้อสินค้าหรือบริการของผู้บริโภค</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>demand (v.)</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: To ask for something very firmly because you think you have the right to it.
Thai: เรียกร้องหรือทวงถามอย่างหนักแน่นเพราะคิดว่าตนมีสิทธิ์</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>export (v.)</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: To send goods to another country for sale.
Thai: ส่งออกสินค้าไปขายยังต่างประเทศ</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>switch (v.)</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: To change or move from one thing to another.
Thai: เปลี่ยนหรือสลับจากสิ่งหนึ่งไปเป็นอีกสิ่งหนึ่ง</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>advise (v.)</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: To tell someone what you think they should do.
Thai: แนะนำหรือให้คำปรึกษาว่าควรทำอย่างไร</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>advice (n.)</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: An opinion or suggestion about what someone should do in a situation.
Thai: คำแนะนำหรือข้อเสนอแนะว่าควรทำอะไรในสถานการณ์หนึ่ง</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>charity (n.)</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: An organization that collects money or goods to help people in need.
Thai: องค์กรการกุศลที่ช่วยเหลือผู้ยากไร้หรือผู้เดือดร้อน</text>
		</card>
		<card>
			<text name='Front'>society (n.)</text>
			<text name='Back'>English: People in general, living together in communities with shared laws and traditions.
Thai: สังคมหรือหมู่ชนที่อยู่ร่วมกันภายใต้กฎเกณฑ์และวัฒนธรรมร่วมกัน</text>
		</card>
	</cards>
</deck>
